Smit Nirmal

 ▼ Toronto, Canada
 M smitmnirmal@gmail.com
 M smitmnirmal.github.io
 L +1 (226) 759-3597

Full-Stack Cloud Engineer with 3+ years of experience in the software development process. Strong knowledge of Object-Oriented Programming Languages, Data Structures and Algorithms. Understanding of SDLC to deliver quality and consistency in performance. True team player with well-developed analytical, problem-solving, interpersonal, written, and verbal communication skills acquired through professional work experience.

Education

Master of Applied Computing, *University of Windsor*

Jan 2019 - Aug 2020 | Windsor, Canada

Bachelors of Computer Engineering, *Ganpat University*

Aug 2014 - May 2018 | Gujarat, India

Skills

Languages

Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, **CSS**

Database

MySQL, MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Redis, MongoDB

Frameworks

Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Angular, Node.js, React, Vue.js, Express.js

Project/Code Management Tools

Git, Jira, Bitbucket, Azure DevOps, Agile, Scrum, Confluence

Cloud Tools

Microsoft Azure, AWS, Heroku

Others

Apache Kafka, Elasticsearch, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Nginx, ¡Query, Postman, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional Experience

Senior Software Engineer, *Egen*

May 2022 - Present

Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Apache Kafka, Jenkins, MySQL, JavaScript, Vue.js, Elasticsearch

- Work with Product Owner, Scrum Master, and lead within the Agile environment and follow Scrum approach.
- Implement RESTful APIs, update existing API endpoints and develop data persistence layer. Also, contribute to Event Driven data integrations using Apache Kafka
- Write automated unit and integration tests for the APIs and test API endpoints manually using Postman.
- · Document API endpoints using Swagger and OpenAPI specification. Use monitoring and alerting dashboards for applications. Update deployment configurations and build pipeline configuration. Publish maven modules to the private module registry.

Software Consultant, BDO Canada

Mar 2021 – May 2022

Technologies: C#, .Net Core, Python, Angular, HTML, SCSS, TypeScript, SQL Server, Azure DevOps, JIRA, Jenkins

- Understand and help refine un-stated requirements & work with the Development Manager, Business Analyst, and Project Manager to define software requirements and to assess the feasibility of solutions within time constraints
- Delivering development activities on time and on budget per project plan by producing quality code that is secure, reliable, reusable, and scalable
- Participate in pull-request reviews and help team members to solve their technical difficulties

Programmer Analyst-Intern, Ontario Teachers' Pension Plan

Jan 2020 – Aug 2020

Technologies: Angular, Python, C#, ASP.NET, Spring Boot, Docker, Kubernetes, MySQL, Apache ActiveMQ, Redis

- Responsible for developing micro-services in Angular, ASP.NET, Spring Boot and Python, also containerized them using Docker and orchestrated using Kubernetes
- Built back-end REST APIs using Flask and .NET; performed Unit and Integration testing
- Duties included meeting with business partners, scrum masters and QA to identify and groom new functionality, upgrade existing functionality and system design changes in Agile-Scrum environment

Achievements

- Attained AZ-204 certification, showcasing mastery in implementing solutions on Microsoft Azure cloud platform.
- Participated in various academic coding competitions and secured top ranks in many of them
- Helped out participants during the coding competition for queries related to technical problems, provided resources for an event